Guide to the Robinson Family Papers 1822-1966 (Bulk 1860-1940) MS 520, MS 2309
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series VIII: Robinson Family Documents (1901-1921)
  This series includes material relating to the Robinson family as a whole as opposed to one particular member of the family. The bulk of the material consists of letters, telegrams, and cards to Dr. Beverley, Anna, Beverley R., Pauline and the younger Anna expressing sympathy after Herman's suicide in 1903. One folder of material details the history of a family home in Garrison, New York which had previously been visited by George Washington and Mrs. Benedict Arnold.
  - Robinson Family, Scrapbook of Letters Received after Death of Herman, 1903 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Robinson Family, Scrapbook of Letters Received after Death of Herman, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Beverley and Anna Robinson, Letters re Wills and Expressing Love to Family Upon Their Death, 1901-1921 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Calling Cards to Family After Death of Herman, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - History of Robinson Family House called "Beverley", 1940 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Poem Read at Robinson Family Reunion, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Series IX: Foster Family (1843-1908)
  This series contains correspondence and memorials of various members of the family of Anna Foster Robinson
  - Subseries 1: Herman Ten Eyck Foster, (1852-1869)
    The letters to Herman Ten Eyck Foster are from his young daughter, Anna Foster Robinson.
    - Herman Ten Eyck Foster, letters received, 1852, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Herman Ten Eyck Foster, Memorials, 1869 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: Pauline Lentilhon Foster, (1843-1847)
    The letters to Pauline Lentilhon Foster, wife of Herman Ten Eyck Foster and mother of Anna Foster Robinson, are from her mother. They detail family events and news.
    - Pauline Lentilhon Foster, letters received, 1843-1847 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: Antoine Lentilhon Foster, (1900-1908)
    This subseries contains letters to Antoine Lentilhon Foster, Anna Foster Robinson's brother. The letters are from Herman Robinson and Charlie Robinson.
    - Antoine Lentilhon Foster, letters received, 1900, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 4: Victoria DuPont Foster, (undated)
    The letters to Victoria DuPont Foster, the wife of Antoine Lentilhon Foster, are from her children.
    - Victoria DuPont Foster, letters received, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Series X: Lentilhon Family (1824-1897)
  This series contains correspondence, volumes, obituaries, genealogies, and property and asset information of the Lentilhon family. Many of the documents in this series are in French.
  - Subseries 1: Eliza Smith Lentilhon, (1824-1857)
    This subseries includes correspondence from Eliza Smith Lentilhon's husband to be, Antoine Lentilhon, and later her children. The reminiscences of Eliza Smith Lentilhon are in English and recount the story of her life and family.
    - Eliza Smith Lentilhon, letters received, 1824-1857 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Reminiscences of Eliza Smith Lentilhon, [1850] (Box 17)
    - Address Book of Eliza Smith Lentilhon, 1852 (Box 17)
  - Subseries 2: Antoine Lentilhon, (1838)
    This subseries includes information on the life of Antoine Lentilhon, the husband of Eliza Smith Lentilhon and grandfather of Anna Foster Robinson, in French and in English.
    - Memorials and Obituaries for Antoine Lentilhon, 1838 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Pauline de Tours Lentilhon, (1876)
    This subseries contains a journal of notes on the Lentilhon family. The journal entries are in French.
    - Pauline de Tours Lentilhon, Documents sur la famille Lentilhon, 1876 (Box 17)
  - Subseries 4: Lentilhon Family Documents, (1836-1897)
    The correspondence, notes, and volumes in this series represent the Lentilhon family in general rather than one individual family member. Many of these materials are in French.
    - Notes on Lentilhon Family Genealogy, 1873-1897 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Lists of Lentilhon Assets, 1836 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Title to Lentilhon Property on Wooster Street, 1836 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series XI: Smith Family (1822-1903)
  This series contains material relating to the Smith Family, which was the family of Anna Foster Robinson's grandmother.
  - Subseries 1: Gamaliel Smith, (1822-1823)
    This subseries contains a letter from Gamaliel Smith, the great-grandfather of Anna Foster Robinson, to other family members. The memorial to Gamaliel Smith includes stories recounted by Eliza Smith Lentilhon of her father and their family in early nineteenth-century New York.
    - Gamaliel Smith, letter sent to Edward L Smith and Mary M. Smith, 1822 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Memorial of Gamaliel Smith, 1823 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: William Smith, (1901-1903)
    The letters to William Smith or "Uncle William" are from Pauline and Anna Robinson. The 1903 letter from Anna briefly describes the service the family had for her brother, Herman.
    - William Smith, letters received, 1901-1903 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Series XII: Ten Eyck Family (1854)
  This series includes correspondence to a member of the family of Anna Foster Robinson's grandmother. The single letter in this series to Catalina Ten Eyck from Anna Foster Robinson describes various family members as well as young Anna Foster Robinson's routine of practicing the piano and reading the Bible.
  - Catalina Ten Eyck, letter received from Anna Foster Robinson, 1854 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Series XIII: Family Genealogies (1875-1896)
  This series contains notes, family trees, and clippings regarding the Robinson's and their extended families. The authors of the genealogy notes are generally Herman or Pauline or else are unidentified. The volume "First Genealogical Notes" includes clippings along with handwritten notes regarding various ancestors.
  - Family Trees, 1890, 1896, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Genealogy Notes, 1883-1896 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Genealogy Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Clippings of Obituaries and Wedding Announcements, 1875-1879, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Volume entitled, "First Genealogical Notes", undated (Box 17)
- Series XIV: Charities (1872-1952)
  This series includes the records of the charity work of female members of the Robinson family, particularly Pauline. The letters and clippings document the need for and the efficacy of the various charities.
  - Subseries 1: Monday Sewing Class, (1872-1952)
    This subseries contains the records of the Monday Sewing Class, a group of women who sewed, and eventually simply paid others to sew, clothes for the poor. Anna Foster Robinson was a founding member of the group and Pauline Robinson later became its President. The records include fabric and monetary contributions, amounts of items of clothing sewn for the poor, and photographs of the members at a luncheon. Besides the loose items, the series also contain two volumes of records. The records also list the prominent female members of the charity such as Anna Eleanor Roosevelt and Sara Delano Roosevelt- the wife and mother of Franklin Delano Roosevelt. The series also contains four short thank you notes to the group from Eleanor Roosevelt..
    - Monday Sewing Class: Lists of Members, 1872-1940 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Monday Sewing Class: Minutes and Reports, 1921-1952 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Monday Sewing Class: Correspondence, 1924-1945 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Monday Sewing Class: Photographs, [1947] (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Monday Sewing Class: Exhibit at Museum of the City of New York for 75th Anniversary, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Record Book of the Monday Sewing Club, 1872-1901, 1921 (Volume 3)
    - Membership and Attendance Book of the Monday Sewing Club, 1877-1887 (Volume 4)
  - Subseries 2: Public Schools as Community Recreation Centers, (1906-1913)
    This subseries documents the efforts to keep public schools open in the evening to provide space for clubs and recreation for local residents. The centers included reading libraries, games, and space for physical activities for teenagers and adults. Various lectures and forms of entertainment were also provided for in many of the schools. Much of the subseries entails correspondence with the Department of Education in New York City. The scrapbook pages mainly include letters responding to Pauline's plea for financial or organizational assistance.
    - Public Schools as Community Recreation Centers, Correspondence, 1906-1913 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Public Schools as Community Recreation Centers, Lists of Committee Members, Clippings, 1907, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Scrapbook of Charity Work, Part 1, 1906-1908 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook of Charity Work, Part 2, 1906-1908 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook of Charity Work, Part 3, 1906-1908 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook of Charity Work, Part 4, 1906-1908 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3: Parks and Playground Association, (1908-1915)
    This series documents Pauline Robinson's involvement in the parks and playground movement which worked to establish playgrounds on roofs and vacant lots. The material includes correspondence, reports, and newspaper clippings. More materials regarding this charity are also in the scrapbook pages in Subseries 2, Public Schools as Community Recreation Centers.
    - Parks and Playground Association, Correspondence and Reports, 1908-1915 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Parks and Playground Association, Clippings, 1910, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 4: West Side Children's Center, (1919-1945)
    This subseries includes reports and of the West Side Children's Center which was part of the larger national group, the Children's Aid Society. The records include a report and some correspondence. The records indicate that Pauline Robinson was President of the West Side Children's Center.
    - Records of West Side Children's Center, 1919-1945 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 5: Junior League, (1902-1951)
    This series documents Pauline Robinson's membership in the Junior League. It includes ephemera from events and a booklet from 1951 that documents the League's thirty year history.
    - Junior League, 1902, 1951, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6: American Ambulance Hospital in Paris, (1917)
    This subseries contains a program from a series of performances to benefit the hospital. The program also indicates that Pauline Robinson was on the Junior Committee for the benefit.
    - Program for Benefit, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Series XV: Visual Materials [1864-1966]
  This series contains photographs, cartes des visite, and glass plate negatives of the Robinson and Lentilhon families and their friends. This series is organized according to person except for the glass plate negatives which are placed together. Most of the photos are posed portraits.
  - Dr. Beverley Robinson, [1864-1894] (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Anna Foster Robinson, 1875, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Beverley R. Robinson, 1877-1893 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Beverley and Herman Robinson, [1880-1885] (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Pauline Robinson, [1884-1922] (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Anna Robinson Butler, 1893 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Antoine Lentilhon, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Eliza Smith Lentilhon, 1891, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified/ Other family or friends, 1875-1966 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Glass Plate Negatives- Anna Foster Robinson, Pauline Robinson, Anna Robinson Butler, 1890-1898 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Glass Plate Negatives- Dr. Beverley Robinson, Unidentified Female, Two Unidentified Males, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Series XVI: Printed Material (1868-1941)
  This series contains ephemera and memorabilia that is not identified as belonging to a particular family member. This series includes a 1919 invitation and program for a reception for the Prince of Wales, later King Edward VIII. It also includes an undated invitation to a talk by "Mrs. Roosevelt" on "Human Rights and Race Relations." The poems appear to be clippings and not writings by a family member.
  - Programs for Shows and Events, 1868-1956 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, 1903-1919 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Church and Diocese Bulletins and News, 1898-1941 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Poems, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Book of Nursery Rhymes, 1830 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - "The Peace Cross Book", A Book of Sermons and Prayers Regarding the Peace Cross in Washington D.C., 1899 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Biographies of Philip Lutley Sclater and Daniel Giraud Elliot, 1914 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Ship Menu, 1903 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Brochures, 1903 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Daily Texts with Verses of Hymns, undated (Box 17)
- Series XVII: Unidentified Writings (1863-1949)
  This series contains material such as letters, notebooks, or writings in which neither the writer nor the owner can be identified.
  - Correspondence, 1895-1949, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Writings and Notes, 1907-1911, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Poultry Account Book, 1867 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Notebook of Dessert Recipes, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Prayers and Scriptures, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Notebook 2, Unidentified Author, Lists of Items and Goods, 1863-1873 (Box 17)
  - Notebook 1, Unidentified Author, Writings, undated (Box 17)
- Series XVIII: Clippings (1870-1956)
  It is unclear who clipped the newspaper articles in this series. Many of the articles relate to politics and current events, particularly World War I.
  - Clippings re politics and current events, 1870-1924 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Clippings re Entertainment, Society, and Stories about "Old New York", 1940-1956, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)